Guide to the Joshua A. Fishman Papers
Department of Special Collections
- Series 2 J. A. Fishman Published and Unpublished Works, 1940s-1990s
  - Italian Language Maintenance Efforts in the United States and the Teacher of Italian in American High Schools and Colleges (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - IT BASKYSK EN IT FYSK (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - Ivrit v'yidish: yitsug khazoti shel yakhasim sotsiyolingvistiyim (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - IZ DO A VEG VI TSU DERNENTERN DI YIDISHE SHTUDIRNDIKE YVGNT IN AMERIKE TSU YIDISHKAYT? (Box 28, Folder 7)
  - The Jewish Daily Forward and Non-English Resources in the USA Today (Box 28, Folder 8)
  - Jewish Languages and Jewish Identity (Box 28, Folder 9)
  - Jewish Students and Yiddishkeit (Box 28, Folder 10)
  - KHASIDISHE MOTIVN BAY PERETSN (Box 28, Folder 11)
  - KHILUKEY-DEYIS VEGN YIDISH-VELTLEKHER SHULARBET (Box 28, Folder 12)
  - Knowing, Using and Liking English as an Additional Language (Box 28, Folder 13)
  - KON DI YIDISHE MEDINE HOBN GELT FAR ALTS? (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - KORESPONDENTS MIT A BIZNESMAN (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - Language and Culture (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - Language and Ethnicity (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - Language and Ethnicity in Bilingual Education (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - Language and Ethnicity in Minority Sociolinguistic Perspective (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - Language and Ethnicity in the Periodical Publications of Four American Ethnic Groups (Box 29, Folder 7)
  - Language and Identity: Keynote Address (Box 29, Folder 8)
  - Language and Nationalism (Box 29, Folder 9)
  - Language Attitude Studies (Box 29, Folder 10)
  - Language, Ethnicity and Racism (Box 29, Folder 11)
  - Language and Society (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Language in Society (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Language in Society: An Introduction to the Sociology of Language [1 of 2] (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Language in Society: An Introduction to the Sociology of Language [2of 2] (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Language in Sociocultural Change (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - Language Loyalty and National Self-Identification (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Language Loyalty in the USA [1 of 8] (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - Language Loyalty in the USA [2 of 8] (Box 30, Folder 8)
  - Language Loyalty in the USA [3 of 8] (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Language Loyalty in the USA [4 of 8] (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - Language Loyalty in the USA [5 of 8] (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - Language Loyalty in the USA [6 of 8] (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - Language Loyalty in the USA [7 of 8] (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - Language Loyalty in the USA [8 of 8] (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - Language Loyalty in the USA--Tables (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - Language Loyalty: Its Functions and Concomitants in Two Bilingual Communities (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - Language Maintenance (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - Language Maintenance and Ethnicity (Box 32, Folder 5)
  - Language Maintenance and Language Shift as a Field of Inquiry (Box 32, Folder 6)
  - Language Maintenance and Language Shift in Certain Urban Immigrant Environments: The Case of Yiddish in the United States (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - Language Maintenance and Language Shift: The American Immigrant Case within a General Theoretical Perspective (Box 33, Folder 2)
  - Language Maintenance and Language Shift: Yiddish and Other Immigrant Languages in the United States (Box 33, Folder 3)
  - Language Maintenance, the "Ethnic Revival" and Diglossia in the USA (Box 33, Folder 4)
  - Language Modernization and Planning in Comparison with Other Types of National Modernization and Planning (Box 33, Folder 5)
  - Language Planning and Language Planning Research: The State of the Art (Box 33, Folder 6)
  - Language Planning in Israel: Solving Terminological Problems (Box 33, Folder 7)
  - Language Policy: Past, Present and Future (Box 33, Folder 8)
  - Language Problems and Types of Political and Sociological Integration: A Conceptual Postscript (Box 33, Folder 9)
  - Language Resources in the United States (Box 33, Folder 10)
  - Language Revitalization (Box 33, Folder 11)
  - Language Spread and Language Policy: Issues, Implications and Case Studies (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - Language Spread: Implications of an International Conference for the Southwest (Box 34, Folder 2)
  - Language Switching and the Interpretation of Conversations (Box 34, Folder 3)
  - Language, Technology and Persuasion in the Middle East: Three Experimental Studies (Box 34, Folder 4)
  - La Utilizacion de las lenguas maternas minoritarias en la ensenanza (Box 34, Folder 5)
  - LAYTISH MAME-LOSHN (Box 34, Folder 6)
  - LEKOVID YUDL MARK (Box 34, Folder 7)
  - Letter to the Editor of the "Forvarts" (Box 34, Folder 8)
  - Letter to the Editor of "Folklife Center News" (Box 34, Folder 9)
  - The Lexicography of Yiddish (Box 34, Folder 10)
  - LIB HOBN UN TZUZOGN (Box 34, Folder 11)
  - Life In the Neighborhood (Box 34, Folder 12)
  - Limitaciones de la Eficacia Escolar Para Inverbir el Desplazamiento Linguistico (Box 34, Folder 13)
  - Linguistic Heterogeneity, Civil Strife and Per Capital Gross National Product in Interpolity Perspective (Box 34, Folder 14)
  - The Link between Language and Ethnicity: Its Importance for the Language Teacher (Box 34, Folder 15)
  - The Lively Life of a "Dead Language" or Everybody Knows that Yiddish Died Long Ago (Box 35, Folder 1)
  - LOMIR DERSHATSN UNDZER OYTSER (Box 35, Folder 2)
  - LOMIR ZIKH GEZEGENEN (Box 35, Folder 3)
  - L'utilisation des langues maternelles minoritaires dans l'enseignement (Box 35, Folder 4)
  - Macrosociolinguistics and the Sociology of Language in the Early Eighties [1 of 4] (Box 35, Folder 5)
  - Macrosociolinguistics and the Sociology of Language in the Early Eighties [2 of 4] (Box 35, Folder 6)
  - Macrosociolinguistics and the Sociology of Language in the Early Eighties [3 of 4] (Box 35, Folder 7)
  - Macrosociolinguistics and the Sociology of Language in the Early Eighties [4 of 4] (Box 35, Folder 8)
  - Maintenance and Loss of Minority Language: Conference Summary (Box 36, Folder 1)
  - Maintien des langues "Renouveau ethniques" et diglossie aux etats unis (Box 36, Folder 2)
  - A MAKHLOYKES LESHEM-SHOMAYEM VEGN...OYSLEYG (Box 36, Folder 3)
  - The Management of Educational Establishments (Box 36, Folder 4)
  - MANI LEYB--ZAYN LEBN UN SHAFN (Box 36, Folder 5)
  - MANUEL DER RAYKHER /YITSKHOK LEYBUSH PERETS (Box 36, Folder 6)
  - MANUEL EL RIKO (Box 36, Folder 7)
  - MAX UN MORITZ UN MOTL UN KOPL (Box 36, Folder 8)
  - Max Weinreich 1894-1969 (Box 36, Folder 9)
  - MAYN BALIBT BUKH (Box 36, Folder 10)
  - MAYN MAME, DI KISHEF-MAKHERIN (Box 36, Folder 11)
  - MAYN TATNS SHIR-HASHIRIM (Box 36, Folder 12)
  - DI MEMSHOLE FUN FOLKSMENTSH (Box 36, Folder 13)
  - A Method for Recording and Analyzing the Prosodic Features of Language (Box 36, Folder 14)
  - A Methodological Check on Three Cross-Polity Studies of Linguistic Homogeneity/Heterogeneity (Box 36, Folder 15)
  - The Minnesota Teacher Attitude Inventory in an American Minority-Group School Setting: Indirect Validation as a Test of Pupil Directedness (Box 36, Folder 16)
  - Minority Language Maintenance and the Ethnic Mother Tongue School (Box 36, Folder 17)
  - Minority Mother Tongues in Education (Box 36, Folder 18)
  - Minority Resistance: Some Comparisons between Interwar Poland and Postwar USA (Box 36, Folder 19)
  - MIT AZA KORN VET MEN KEYN BROYT NIT BAKN (Box 36, Folder 20)
  - MIT DEM YONTEF PEYSEKH ZAYNEN FARBUNDN ON A SHIR MINHOGIM VOS MEN MUZ UFHITN (Box 36, Folder 21)
  - MIT 50 YOR TSURIK IN FILADELFIYE: A YUGNT-ZHURNAL AF YIDISH (Box 37, Folder 1)
  - MIT VOS IZ YIDISH ANDERSH? (Box 37, Folder 2)
  - A Model for Bilingual and Bidialectical Education (Box 37, Folder 3)
  - Modeling Rationales in Corpus Planning: Modernity and Tradition in Images of the Good Corpus (Box 37, Folder 4)
  - Mother Tongue Claiming in the United States Since 1960: Trends and Correlates Related to the "Revival of Ethnicity" [1 of 3] (Box 37, Folder 5)
  - Mother Tongue Claiming in the United States Since 1960: Trends and Correlates Related to the "Revival of Ethnicity" [2 of 3] (Box 37, Folder 6)
  - Mother Tongue Claiming in the United States Since 1960: Trends and Correlates Related to the "Revival of Ethnicity" [3 of 3] (Box 37, Folder 7)
  - Mother Tongues as Media of Instruction in the United States (Box 37, Folder 8)
  - Moving to the Suburbs: Its Possible Impact on the Role of the Jewish Minority in American Community Life (Box 37, Folder 9)
  - The MTAI in an American-Group Setting: I. Differences between Test Characteristics for Norm and Non-Norm Populations (Box 37, Folder 10)
  - The Minnesota Teacher Attitude Inventory in an American Minority-Group School Setting: II. Indirect Validation as a Test of Pupil-Directedness (Box 38, Folder 1)
  - Multilingualism (Box 38, Folder 2)
  - The Multiple Prediction of Phonological Variables in a Bilingual Speech Community (Box 38, Folder 3)
  - My Life through My Work: My Work through My Life (Box 38, Folder 4)
  - Nathan Birnbaum's First Phase: From Zionism to Eastern European Jewry (in commemoration of his 120th birthday) (Box 38, Folder 5)
  - Nathan Birnbaum's Second Phase: Champion of Yiddish and Yiddish Cultural Autonomy (Box 38, Folder 6)
  - Nathan Birnbaum's Third Phase: The Activization of Jewish Sanctity (Box 38, Folder 7)
  - Nathan Birnbaum's Three "Rendezvous" in Tshernovits (Box 38, Folder 8)
  - Nathan Birnbaum's View of American Jewry (Box 39, Folder 1)
  - Nationality--Nationalism and Nation--Nationalism (Box 39, Folder 2)
  - National Languages and Languages of Wider Communication in the Developing Nations (Box 39, Folder 3)
  - Nationalism and Experimental Studies of Language Behavior (Box 39, Folder 4)
  - A NAYE FARTEYDIKUNG FUN YIDISH IN DI KHAREYDISHE KRAYZN (Box 39, Folder 5)
  - DER MAYER LERER (Box 39, Folder 6)
  - The Need for Language Planning in the United States (Box 39, Folder 7)
  - Negative Stereotypes Concerning Americans among American-Born Children Receiving Various Types of Minority-Group Education [1 of 2] (Box 39, Folder 8)
  - Negative Stereotypes Concerning Americans among American-Born Children Receiving Various Types of Minority-Group Education [2 of 2] (Box 40, Folder 1)
  - NEKHTN UN HAYNT (Box 40, Folder 2)
  - Neo-Marxist and Post-Structural Critiques of Classical Language Planning (Box 40, Folder 3)
  - Never Say Die [1 of 10] (Box 40, Folder 4)
  - Never Say Die [2 of 10] (Box 40, Folder 5)
  - Never Say Die [3 of 10] (Box 41, Folder 1)
  - Never Say Die [4 of 10] (Box 41, Folder 2)
  - Never Say Die [5 of 10] (Box 41, Folder 3)
  - Never Say Die [6 of 10] (Box 41, Folder 4)
  - Never Say Die [7 of 10] (Box 42, Folder 1)
  - Never Say Die [8 of 10] (Box 42, Folder 2)
  - Never Say Die [9 of 10] (Box 42, Folder 3)
  - Never Say Die [10 of 10] (Box 42, Folder 4)
  - A New Departure in American Graduate Education (Box 42, Folder 5)
  - New Directions in College Board Research (Box 42, Folder 6)
  - New Worlds to Conquer in the Sociology of Language (Box 43, Folder 1)
  - New York City's Non-English Dailies and the Newspaper Deliverymen's Strike of December 1958 (Box 43, Folder 2)
  - A NIT-ANTIKVARISHER TSUGANG TSU DER YIDISHER FOLKLOR-FORSHUNG (Box 43, Folder 3)
  - NOKH DER MITLSHUL-VOS VAYTER? (Box 43, Folder 4)
  - A Non-Antiquarian Approach to Folklore Research (Box 43, Folder 5)
  - Non-English Language Ethnic Community Schools in the USA: Instruments of More than Literacy and Less than Literacy (Box 43, Folder 6)
  - Non-English Language Resources of the United States (A Preliminary Return Visit) (Box 43, Folder 7)
  - Non-Intellective Factors as Predictors, as Criteria, and as Contingencies in the Selection and Guidance of College Students: A Socio-Psychological Analysis (Box 43, Folder 8)
  - DI UVDES FUN MIZREKH-EYROPEYISHE YIDN (Box 43, Folder 9)
  - NOSN BIRNBOYMS DRAY TSHERNOVITSER KONFERENTSN (Box 43, Folder 10)
  - NOSN BIRNBOYMS DRITER PEYRIK: DI DERHEYBUNG UN FARTIFUNG FUN DER YIDISHER KEDUSHE (Box 43, Folder 11)
  - NOSN BIRNBOYMS ERSHTER PEYRIK: AFN VEG TSU YIDISH UN TSUM MIZREKH-EYROPEYISHN YIDNTUM (Box 44, Folder 1)
  - NOSN BIRNBOYMS TSUGANG TSUM AMERIKANER YIDNTUM ONHEYB 20STN YORHUNDERT (Box 44, Folder 2)
  - NOSN BIRNBOYMS TSVEYTER PEYRIK: DER KEMFER FAR YIDISHER KULTUR-OYTONOMIYE (Box 44, Folder 3)
  - A Note on Jenkins' "Improved Method for Tetrachoric r" (Box 44, Folder 4)
  - "Nothing New Under the Sun" (Ecclesiastics 1:9): A Case Study of Early Stages of the "Language and Ethnocultural Identity" Linkage [1 of 2] (Box 44, Folder 5)
  - "Nothing New Under the Sun" (Ecclesiastics 1:9): A Case Study of Early Stages of the "Language and Ethnocultural Identity" Linkage [2 of 2] (Box 44, Folder 6)
  - The Official Languages of Israel and Police Attitudes and Knowledge Concerning Them (Box 44, Folder 7)
  - On Fostering Bilingualism Among Professionals: A New Challenge for Bilingual Education (Box 44, Folder 8)
  - DER ONHEYB FUN VISIKN AHAVES-YIDISH UN SINES-YIDISH IN MIZREKH-EYROPE (Box 45, Folder 1)
  - One Hundred Issues of IJSL (Box 45, Folder 2)
  - On the Limits of Ethnolinguistic Democracy (Box 45, Folder 3)
  - On Reservation Residence and the Survival of Native American Languages (Box 45, Folder 4)
  - On the Peculiar Problems of Smaller National Languages (Box 45, Folder 5)
  - ORIYENTIRTKAYT UN ORGANIZIRTKAYT-DOS NAYE GEZETS LETOYVES TSVEY-SHPRAKHIKER BILDUNG (Box 45, Folder 6)
  - DER OYTSER FUN YIDISHN FOLKLOR (Box 45, Folder 7)
  - Patterns of American Self-Identification among Children of a Minority Group (Box 45, Folder 8)
  - A PEKL KSOVIM FUN A KHOYVEV-YIDISH UN YIDISHKAYT-MAYN LERER FISHL HERSHTEYN (Box 45, Folder 9)
  - Per un Educazione Bilingue (Box 45, Folder 10)
  - The Phenomenological and Linguistic Pilgrimage of Yiddish: Some Examples of Functional and Structural Pidginization and Depidginization (Box 45, Folder 11)
  - Philosophies of Bilingual Education in Societal Perspective (Box 45, Folder 12)
  - The Philosophical and Methodological Critique of "Classical" Language Planning Theory (Box 45, Folder 13)
  - PLANIRTER SHPRAKH-IBERRUK (Box 45, Folder 14)
  - PLURALIZM IN DER YISROYELDIKER YIDISHKAYT (Box 45, Folder 15)
  - The Politics of Bilingual Education (Box 45, Folder 16)
  - Positive Bilingualism: Some Overlooked Rationales and Forefathers (Box 46, Folder 1)
  - Post-Exilic Jewish Languages and Pidgins/Creoles: Two Mutually Clarifying Perspectives (Box 46, Folder 2)
  - Post-Imperial English [1 of 4] (Box 46, Folder 3)
  - Post-Imperial English [2 of 4] (Box 46, Folder 4)
  - Post-Imperial English [3 of 4] (Box 46, Folder 5)
  - Post-Imperial English [4 of 4] (Box 46, Folder 6)
  - Prefatory Remarks: The Worm Turns (Box 47, Folder 1)
  - PROBE-ARTIKLEN FAR DER YIDISHER TSAYTUNG "DER TOG" (Box 47, Folder 2)
  - PROBLEMEN FUN SHPRAKHIKER HASHOVES-AVEYDE: A SOTSIYOLINGVISTISHER TSUGANG TSUM TSVISHN-DOYRESDIKN HEMSHEKH FUN YIDISH IN DI NIT-KHAREYDISHE KRAYZN (Box 47, Folder 3)
  - Problems of Research Collaboration and Cooperation (Box 47, Folder 4)
  - Problems of Secondary and Higher Education Among Mexican-Americans in the American Southwest (Box 47, Folder 5)
  - Progress in Language Planning: International Perspectives (Box 47, Folder 6)
  - Progress in Language Planning: A Few Concluding Statements (Box 47, Folder 7)
  - Prospects for Reversing Language Shift (RLS) in Australia: Evidence from Its Aboriginal and Immigrant Languages (Box 47, Folder 8)
  - Psychology and Sociology (JAF) Book Reviews on the American Jewish Scene (Box 47, Folder 9)
  - The Psychology of Cognition, the Philosophy of Secondary Education and the Testing of Aptitude and Achievement (Box 47, Folder 10)
  - Publicly Subsidized Pluralism: The European and the American Context (Box 47, Folder 11)
  - Publications Honoring JAF (Box 47, Folder 12)
  - Puerto Rican Intellectuals in New York: Quantitative Analysis of Twenty Bilingual Interviews (Box 47, Folder 13)
  - Puerto Ricans in Our Press (Box 48, Folder 1)
  - Putting the "Socio" Back into the Sociolinguistic Enterprise (Box 48, Folder 2)
  - Questionnaire for Young Returnees from Israel (1953) (Box 48, Folder 3)
  - Readings in the Sociology of Jewish Languages (Box 48, Folder 4)
  - Readings in the Sociology of Language [1 of 2] (Box 48, Folder 5)
  - Readings in the Sociology of Language [2 of 2] (Box 48, Folder 6)
  - Reflections on Ten Years of IJSL (Box 48, Folder 7)
  - Reflections on the Current State of Language Planning (Box 48, Folder 8)
  - Remarks of the Chairman: Improving Criteria for Educational and Psychological Measurement (Box 48, Folder 9)
  - Remarks on Acknowledging the JBC Award (Box 48, Folder 10)
  - Replyk oangeande twatiligens (Box 48, Folder 11)
  - Research on National Languages (Box 49, Folder 1)
  - Research Outline for Comparative Studies of Language Planning (Box 49, Folder 2)
  - Reversing Language Shift: Australia: Aboriginal and Immigrant Languages (Box 49, Folder 3)
  - Reversing Language Shift: Author's Preface (Box 49, Folder 4)
  - Reversing Language Shift: Basque and Frisian (Box 49, Folder 5)
  - Reversing Language Shift: Book Reviews (Box 49, Folder 6)
  - Reversing Language Shift: Irish (Box 49, Folder 7)
  - Reversing Language Shift: How Threatened is Threatened? (Box 49, Folder 8)
  - Reversing Language Shift: Limitations on School-Effectiveness in RLS, in General, and on Mother Tongue Acquisition, in Particular (Box 49, Folder 9)
  - Reversing Language Shift: Maori (Box 49, Folder 10)
  - Reversing Language Shift: Navajo, Spanish, Yiddish (Box 49, Folder 11)
  - Reversing Language Shift: Reviewing the Past, Planning the Future (Box 49, Folder 12)
  - Reversing Language Shift: Successes, Failures, Doubts and Dilemmas (Box 49, Folder 13)
  - Reversing Language Shift: Theoretical Recapitulation: What is RLS and How Can It Succeed? (Box 50, Folder 1)
  - Reversing Language Shift: Three Dilemmas of Organized Efforts to Reverse Language Shift (Box 50, Folder 2)
  - Reversing Language Shift: Three Success Stories: (More or Less): Hebrew, French in Quebec and Catalan (Box 50, Folder 3)
  - Reversing Language Shift: What This Book Is About and Why It Is Needed (Box 50, Folder 4)
  - Reversing Language Shift: Where and why Does Language Shift Occur? (Box 50, Folder 5)
  - Reversing Language Shift: Why Bother Trying to Reverse Language Shift (Is It Possible to Do So? Is It Desirable?) (Box 50, Folder 6)
  - The Rise and Fall of the Ethnic Revival [1 of 12] (Box 50, Folder 7)
  - The Rise and Fall of the Ethnic Revival [2 of 12] (Box 51, Folder 1)
  - The Rise and Fall of the Ethnic Revival [3 of 12] (Box 51, Folder 2)
  - The Rise and Fall of the Ethnic Revival [4 of 12] (Box 51, Folder 3)
  - The Rise and Fall of the Ethnic Revival [5 of 12] (Box 51, Folder 4)
  - The Rise and Fall of the Ethnic Revival [6 of 12] (Box 51, Folder 5)
  - The Rise and Fall of the Ethnic Revival [7 of 12] (Box 52, Folder 1)
  - The Rise and Fall of the Ethnic Revival [8 of 12] (Box 52, Folder 2)
  - The Rise and Fall of the Ethnic Revival [9 of 12] (Box 52, Folder 3)
  - The Rise and Fall of the Ethnic Revival [10 of 12] (Box 53, Folder 1)
  - The Rise and Fall of the Ethnic Revival [11 of 12] (Box 53, Folder 2)
  - The Rise and Fall of the Ethnic Revival [12 of 12] (Box 53, Folder 3)
  - The Role of Ethnicity in Social Theory (Box 53, Folder 4)
  - Safot Zarot B'Artsot Habrit (Foreign Languages in the United States) (Box 54, Folder 1)
  - Score Gain and Score Loss from "Preliminary" to "Final" Testing (Box 54, Folder 2)
  - SEKULERE YIDISHKAYT (Box 54, Folder 3)
  - Selected Dimensions of Language Planning: A Comparative Analysis (Box 54, Folder 4)
  - Semantic Independence and Degree of Bilingualism in Two Puerto Rican Communities (Box 54, Folder 5)
  - Separatism and Integrationism: A Social Psychological Analysis of Editorial Content in New York Newspapers of Minority Groups (Box 54, Folder 6)
  - SERBISH UN KROATISH (Box 54, Folder 7)
  - A SHMUES VEGN DER FEDERATSIYE (Box 54, Folder 8)
  - SHOLEM ALEYKHEMS BATSIYUNGEN MIT PERETSN UN MENDELEN (Box 54, Folder 9)
  - SHOLEM ALEYKHEM DER ROMANIST (Box 54, Folder 10)
  - Should Teachers Strike? (Box 54, Folder 11)
  - SHOYEL GUTMANS PROFIL (Box 54, Folder 12)
  - SHPALTUNG, SHREK UN HOFNUNG (Box 54, Folder 13)
  - SHPRAKHIKAYT IN HAYNTIKN YISROYEL (Box 54, Folder 14)
  - SHPRAKHIKER MONZIM (Box 54, Folder 15)
  - SHPRAKH-PLANIRUNG BAY DI UMES-HAOYLEM (Box 54, Folder 16)
  - SHPRAKH-PLANIRUNG, OYSLEYG-PLANIRUNG UN YIDISH (Box 54, Folder 17)
  - DI SHTUREMISHE BALKONEN (Box 54, Folder 18)
  - DI SHULYUGNT-IRE SHTRIKHN UN HOFNUNGEN (Box 54, Folder 19)
  - The Significance of the Ethnic Community Mother Tongue School (Box 55, Folder 1)
  - Situational Measures of Normative Language Views in Relation to Person, Place and Topic among Puerto Rican Bilinguals (Box 55, Folder 2)
  - Social Change and Student Values: Discussion (Box 55, Folder 3)
  - The Social-Psychological Analysis of Proverb-Content (Box 55, Folder 4)
  - Social-Psychological Theory for Selecting and Guiding College Students (Box 55, Folder 5)
  - Social Science Research Relevant to American Jewish Education, 1958 (Box 55, Folder 6)
  - Social Science Research Relevant to American Jewish Education, 1959 (Box 55, Folder 7)
  - Social Theory and Ethnography: Language and Ethnicity in Eastern Europe (Box 55, Folder 8)
  - The Societal Basis of the Intergenerational Continuity of Additional Languages (Box 55, Folder 9)
  - Societal Bilingualism Today and Tomorrow (A Preliminary Formulation) (Box 55, Folder 10)
  - Societal Factors Predictive of Linguistic Homogeneity/ Heterogeneity at the Inter-Polity Level [1 of 4] (Box 55, Folder 11)
  - Societal Factors Predictive of Linguistic Homogeneity/ Heterogeneity at the Inter-Polity Level [2 of 4] (Box 55, Folder 12)
  - Societal Factors Predictive of Linguistic Homogeneity/ Heterogeneity at the Inter-Polity Level [3 of 4] (Box 55, Folder 13)
  - Societal Factors Predictive of Linguistic Homogeneity/ Heterogeneity at the Inter-Polity Level [4 of 4] (Box 56, Folder 1)
  - A Sociolinguistic Census of a Bilingual Neighborhood (Box 56, Folder 2)
  - Sociolinguistic Foundations of Bilingual Education (Box 56, Folder 3)
  - The Sociolinguistic "Normalization" of the Jewish People (Box 56, Folder 4)
  - Sociolinguistic Perspective on Education [1 of 6] (Box 56, Folder 5)
  - Sociolinguistic Perspective on Education [2 of 6] (Box 56, Folder 6)
  - Sociolinguistic Perspective on Education [3 of 6] (Box 56, Folder 7)
  - Sociolinguistic Perspective on Education [4 of 6] (Box 57, Folder 1)
  - Sociolinguistic Perspective on Education [5 of 6] (Box 57, Folder 2)
  - Sociolinguistic Perspective on Education [6 of 6] (Box 57, Folder 3)
  - Sociolinguistic Perspective on Education: Readings in Preparation for Article [1 of 2] (Box 57, Folder 4)
  - Sociolinguistic Perspective on Education: Readings in Preparation for Article [2 of 2] (Box 58, Folder 1)
  - Sociolinguistic Perspective on Internal Linguistic Tensions and Their Impact on External Relations (Box 58, Folder 2)
  - Sociolinguistic Perspective on Second Language Acquisition (Box 58, Folder 3)
  - Sociolinguistic Perspective on the Study of Bilingualism (Box 58, Folder 4)
  - Sociolinguistics: A Brief Introduction (Box 58, Folder 5)
  - Sociolinguistics and Education (Box 58, Folder 6)
  - Sociolinguistics and National Development (Box 58, Folder 7)
  - Sociolinguistics and the Language Problems of Developing Countries (Box 58, Folder 8)
  - The Sociolinguistics of Nationalism (Box 59, Folder 1)
  - Sociolinguistique (Box 59, Folder 2)
  - La Socio-linguistique et les problemes Linguistiques des pays en voie de developpement (Box 59, Folder 3)
  - The Sociologist as Biographer: Reflections on Taking Leave (Box 59, Folder 4)
  - The Sociologist as a Consultant in the Field of Education (Box 59, Folder 5)
  - The Sociology of Bilingual Education [1 of 2] (Box 59, Folder 6)
  - The Sociology of Bilingual Education [2 of 2] (Box 59, Folder 7)